

NICOLAS NUCIFORA

GAMEPLAY PROGRAMMER

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Gameplay programmer with about 2 years of personal experience in game development. Working with a small team on development of a video game as University of Catania's experiment. Seeking Gameplay programmer position to utilize my knowledge and skills and improve them further.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: C++, C, Java, C#
- Strong C++/C# programming skills, with good knowledge of object oriented programming
- Good knowledge of Game Design process, from brain storming to game development
- Ability to work in an iterative environment with game designers to quickly prototype gameplay features
- Capability to write clean code, keeping attention to write efficient code.
- Knowledge of common algorithms, data structures and patterns
- Good knowledge of project versioning using Git

CONTACTS AND PORTFOLIO

Contacts:

Giardini-Naxos (ME), Sicily, Italy Mobile: +39 388 8735636 nuciforanicolas@gmail.com

Portfolio: www.nuciforanicolas.github.io https://github.com/NuciforaNicolas? tab=repositories

WORK HISTORY

Salesforce Developer

Deloitte - Rome (April 2021 - Current)

- Tested functionality, performed debugging and carried out modifications to conduct quality checks.
- Delivered front-end and back-end architecture and functionality by translating development requirements.
- Development and enhancement of salesforce and vlocity feature, according to clients requirements.
- Refactoring of existing code to improve code quality and reduce effort
- Project Management through Jira and versioning using Git
- Team and Client communication and collaboration

Gameplay Programmer

University of Catania - Catania (Sept 2020 - Current)

- Development, with a small team, of a 2.5D horror game as experiment for university of Catania
- Worked on gameplay mechanics (player movement, environment interaction, animations, scripting) and the principle enemy's artificial intelligence
- Solid knowledge of Unity 3D and C#
- Works with other team members to develop features in accordance with the scope and vision of the game
- Prioritized tasks and carefully managed time to consistently meet delivery dates.
- Created plans and communicated deadlines to ensure projects were completed on time.
- Tasks management using Trello
- Project Management using Git

EDUCATION

University of Catania

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science -September 2017 - April 2021

Vote: 110/110

Career path:

- Object oriented programming with C++
- Studied principle design patterns and software engineering with Java
- Game Development with Unity 3D and C#
- Algorithm and data structures
- Computer Network with C
- Operative System
- Internet Security
- Data Base with SQL
- Mobile Development with Android Studio
- Math: linear algebra

HOBBY AND INTEREST

I'm appassionate about video games. I really love play them outside of work. In my free time, I like to read fantasy books or go to the gym.